So in today's video I will talk about
which health insurance policy I have.
Many times you people ask, Ma'am, please
tell me about your policy, which
policy are you holding and why?  So
today I will tell you which
health insurance policies I have and
why I am holding them.
So the policy I have is Neevapa
Health Companion Variant 2022.
I have been holding this policy since 2016.  First of all the
question will arise that why Neevapa?  So
I myself am associated with Niva Bupa since I
think 2009-2010, so more than 10 years have passed since
I am associated with Niva Bupa
and I have first hand experience
of claims and I believe in the company, I have
complete conviction with this company, that is why I have
my policy with Niva Bupa, if
you see in Niva Bupa, that is a
global player, so their global
presence there is huge,
they operate in many countries like
Europe, Asia, Latin America, Middle East,
Saudi Arabia and India through joint venture.
Like here
Neema Bupa operates through joint venture in Saudi Arabia also.
So millions
of lives are covered by Bupa.  In
the form of insurance.  Bupa
is a healthcare provider.  You will see that there are health
clinics also there.  Globally it
is quite remade and a very strong system.
So because of that I am with Neevapa
policy.  Ported its policy to Nivapa in 2016.
Before that, I had my own personal
policy from United India which was
done by my parents and Gurpreet
's parents had done New India.  So
we have ported the combination of both of them here in
Niva Bupa Health Companion.  Mine could
not be ported because you could
port only one.  The dates of both were on
different dates.  So
we ported the policies of Gurpreet and his children.  I was
added to the As a Fresh policy.  So as
you can see my policy is due in February
every year.  So
I renewed it on 30th January.  These details are mentioned
in your policy document such as
policy number, customer ID and address.  So
this is the policy document.  Here you
will see that this is an insurance certificate.
Policy commencement date is 5th February 2025.   The
expiry date is 4th February 2026.  The sum
insured is ₹30 lakh.  The variant, as
I mentioned, is the 2022 variant.  And this
family floater policy is for all four of us.
Mine, my husband's, son's, daughter's.
So we have taken a combine policy.  Now you will
understand that family floater policy
is taken where you are
taking the policy for the families.  So here the
premium is less and we make sure that
cover is provided to everyone.
All the members of the family should be covered in the policy.
You never know when someone might
need hospitalization.  That's why we have included
children in the policy right from the beginning.  Our son was
born in 2004 and that is also added in the policy
since birth and daughter was born in 2009 and
that is also added in the policy since birth.   There
are details about which riders have chosen.  Here are the details of our F.
Our base sum insured is Rs 30 lakh.   The
no claim bonus as of now is ₹20
lakh and the refill amount is ₹30 lakh.  And
your safeguard sum is insured in Niva BPA.  There is a rider due to which
your sum insured
increases every time due to inflation.  So 5% increases almost every year.
So this also accumulates 247.  If
I want to claim as of today,
I can claim Rs 82.47 lakh from the base policy.   I can
claim Rs 82.5 lakh from my base policy.
If you remove the refill and keep it
aside, then
I can take a single claim of Rs 52.5 lakh from the base
policy.  Now here what I was telling you
that I am covered, this is my premium
amount.  And so I am covered insured
with Nivapa since 5th Feb 2016
I ported my policy in 2016.  I have been
covered in Niwapa ever since.  These are the benefits of the policy.
What is covered?  How
is it covered?  Are there waiting periods?
Well, there is no waiting period now.  It has been so many
years since the policy was implemented.  What
are the exclusions?  What will not be covered?  All the details are
mentioned here in the policy document.
Like it is in your policy document also.
Along with this we have taken a super top
up policy.  Which is a pure
backup plan.  Meaning, if ever this cover falls short for you, then the
super top up policy will come in handy.
Now here I would like to tell you one thing.  I
want to enhance my cover.  But due to certain
medical conditions the cover is not increasing.
Due to which we have decided that
next year we will split our policy and
increase the cover.  And Since Our Son Is Now
21.  So probably you can continue with this policy for now.
But after a few years,
after two to three years, we will make a separate policy.
Son's is different.  There is
also a
video on our channel on how to increase the cover by splitting the policy.  I posted it some time ago.
Its link is below.  You
should check what you can do if your cover is not increasing.
Now let's come to my
Super Topup policy.  So, Super Topup,
as I said, is only a backup cover, so that if
any such claim comes, a single claim which is of a
very high amount and you have to bear it out of
pocket, then Super Topper
will come to the rescue.  He will work for more than Rs 10 lakh.  That
is why my policy mentions
deductible opted at ₹1 lakh.  My renewal is
with me.  It is renewed at the same time in
February every year.  Here all
four of us are covered in Super Topup also.  This is
90 lakh super top up.  Some loyalty
addition has been added to this because we have not
taken any claim of Rs 3,75,000, so my cover is Rs 93.75.
So here you know that pre-
existing diseases need to be mentioned.
And here why am I telling you
that we should not rely only on super top up.
If we say that we can take super top up
even after taking a policy of Rs 5 lakh or base cover of Rs 10 lakh.  Because the
deductible is Rs
10 lakh.  You can take it but it
is not advisable.  There is a reason for that.
Because Super Topup is a very basic cover.
Your premium is looking at how
low you are.  Here the premium I have paid for 3 years is
₹9,700.
Approximately ₹3500 premium has been paid for 3 years.
But against that what I am getting covered is
room category single private.
Ok?  The rest of your things are
restricted in road ambulances.
Along with this, if you see the main thing here,
modern treatments are covered up to the sum
insured and some limit is applicable.  Now let us
also see what is the limit
in my policy, I am searching for
modern here.  So here you have it, what are the limits of modern treatments.
So
all these treatments are covered in modern treatments.
This is the below you will see
submits.  My sublimit on all these things is
5 lakhs on some, ₹ 1.5 lakhs on some
, 3.5 lakhs on some, 2 lakhs on others, so the
maximum payout will be this much only if these
conditions are met.  I can say that my cover has become worth
crores of rupees after getting the super top up.
But actually when I need it, this much will be the only
pay in Super Topper.
So I also want to increase my base cover
next year I'm going to do the split
process.  So that is why it is said that it is
important for you to read your policy document.
What is covered in it and what is not covered.  If
something is available at a cheaper price, it may be
missing some of the ingredients.  But I know it will
act as a good backup.  Till the time something is
needed where I am getting
traditional treatment.
This policy of mine is going to be very useful there.  90
lace cover is a lot.  If you
look from the cover point of view, it is for a single claim.  So
I have made one claim till date from my policy
which was absolutely smooth.  Gradually
I have been increasing my cover.
Meaning, gradually I have increased my cover.
One thing I am very particular
about is that I get my health
checkup done every year through the policy.
I get complimentary annual health checkup
in my base policy.  I make it available every year
for all the four members.
Our policy is due in February.
Along with renewal, within a week we schedule
everyone's appointments one by one as per their
availability and get
everyone's full body checkup done.  So that
you can know whether there is any deviation in your health.
And if any company is
giving some benefit then why not all that.
So in this way I would suggest that you also
open your policy document.  See what
policy you have taken, what according to you is right and
what is not right, but one thing is for sure
that you should take more cover and not less cover because
at times what will happen is that some
medical condition will be diagnosed in future then
you will not be able to enhance the cover, so it is better that you buy
your health
insurance cover adequate right now, so this is what I
wanted to share today, be it any
comment, tell me anything, any
feedback, tell me, have you checked in your policy
what is covered and what is not covered, have
you taken a single policy base or have
you taken single plus plus super top up
combination.  How have you
planned the security and risk of your family,
please
tell us in the comment section.  And if you want to reach out
to our team, the numbers are mentioned below.
You can reach out.  You
can fill out Google Forms.  Our team will connect you.
Quick reminder before we go, if
you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, do so.
So that you get the
right information at the right time.  See you
in the next video.  Till then stay safe.
Take care.  Bye.